Contact

kellsaro@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/kellsaro (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Extraer, transformar y cargar (ETL) Análisis de datos Desarrollo de software

Languages

Español (Native or Bilingual)
Inglés (Professional Working)
Francés (Professional Working)

Certifications

EF SET Certificate

Triplebyte Certified Generalist Software Engineer

Maykell Sánchez Romero

Software Developer at InfoTech Research Group Ecuador

Summary

I'm Full Stack Web Developer interested in continuous learning and happy programming and productivity being in the zone. I'm a proactive person with huge abilities for research and problem solving. I like to bring added-value solutions to enterprise/customers problems & needs. I like team work and I'm always learning new things and sharing it with people around me.

Previous experiences includes development/customization of ERP, PMS, HIS, Electronic Invoice Management and Transportation Planning System.

Experience

OpenlabEC

Software Developer

February 2024 - Present (8 months)

Quito, Pichincha, Ecuador

Development of web applications, Extract-Transform-Load pipelines and Data Analysis for OpenLab's clients.

DOMINION GLOBAL

Ruby on Rails Developer

August 2022 - January 2024 (1 year 6 months)

Panamá

Development of new features for client's systems. Support for legacy features, code cleaning and code testing improvements.

Admios

Senior Software Developer

August 2019 - August 2022 (3 years 1 month)

Desarrollo de nuevas funcionalidades en Ruby on Rails para clientes de Admios. Desarrollo de herramientas internas a la organización basado en el SDK de Slack.

Laverix Deep Insights
Architect / Developer
February 2019 - April 2019 (3 months)

Ecuador

Architecture and development of an application for web mining and creating reports about Insurance Market Data.

Ministry of Interior - Ecuador ICT Analist April 2015 - November 2018 (3 years 8 months) MDI, Ecuador

Architecture's design of the Control Migration Information System of Ecuador(SIMIEC) and development of different modules. Development of solutions for integrations with 3M AT9000 Full Page Passport Scanner and CROSSMATCH PATROL_ID devices. Management of Git repository and development of reports.

Creation of reports and visualizations of migration data in Excel/LibreOffice. In some cases the R Data Analysis language was used.

Gabriel Paladines S.A.
Software Developer
April 2015 - December 2015 (9 months)
Ecuador

Architecture's design and development of Electronic Invoice System. Integration with ERP.

AEC Inter S.A.

Software Developer

January 2015 - December 2015 (1 year)

Ecuador

Architecture's design and development of the LOTAIP System. LOTAIP System's aim is to support the Transparecy and Public Information Access Law of Ecuador.

Carrasco y Asociados Cia. Ltda. SpyralSoftware Senior Java Developer October 2014 - March 2015 (6 months) Ecuador

Software support and development of new functionalities for the Human Resources Management System "Spyral Teams".

GMixon

Ruby on Rails developer May 2013 - October 2014 (1 year 6 months)

France

Software support and development of new functionalities for the Gmixon's Project Management System. The job done in freelance modality.

Transtur Varadero Software Developer Specialist March 2011 - March 2013 (2 years 1 month) Cuba

Development of custom ERP for turist transportation activities management.

Peoplewalking Java Developer 2010 - 2012 (2 years) Spain

Software support for different implementations of ERP Openbravo and development of new functionalities. Job done in freelance modality.

Universidad de las Ciencias Informáticas Software Developer/Assistant Teacher September 2004 - July 2010 (5 years 11 months) Havana, Cuba

Modules development for the Hospital Information System alas-HIS, HL7 integrator. Programming teacher.

Education

Universidad de La Habana Licenciado, Ciencias de la Computación · (1999 - 2004)

Universidad de las Ciencias Informáticas Máster, Desarrollo de Software · (2006 - 2010)